Animation Number 1
Demon
The name Oshino Shinobu has become plenty comfortable to us.
（阿良々木(あららぎ)）
忍野(おしの) 忍(しのぶ)という名前は
僕たちの間では
既に十分になじんでいて
何の違和感もなく
Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 2
We feel no discomfort with it. The name just fits in such a satisfactory way.
Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 2
胸にストンと
落ちるものである
Her original name, Kiss-shot Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade...
もともとあった
キスショット･アセロラオリオン･
ハートアンダーブレードという
彼女の名前は
Kiss-Shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade
Animation Number 3
...is already something of the past, even for her.
Kiss-Shot Acerola-Orion Heart-Under-Blade
Animation Number 3
彼女にとってさえ
既に過去のものと
なっているだろう
Vampire
Animation Number 4
Memory
Past
Animation Number 4
Things concluded
Things that possibly never happened
Animation Number 4
Their veracity is unconfirmed.
How Shinobu is who she currently is...
忍が 今の忍であること
Shinobu
Animation Number 4
Iron-blooded Vampire
Animation Number 5
For an iron-blooded, hot-blooded, cold-blooded vampire...
Iron-blooded Vampire
Animation Number 5
鉄血(てっけつ)にして 熱血にして
冷血の吸血鬼
Iron-blooded Vampire
Animation Number 5
Hot-blooded Vampire
Cold-blooded Vampire
Animation Number 5
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
Casting away the form and name of Kiss-shot
Acerola-Orion Heart-under-blade
Animation Number 6
You could say the fact that Shinobu is who she is now is a result of her occasional whims.
今の忍であってくれることは
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
But the truth is,
above all else she is my salvation.
Animation Number 7
彼女の その時々の
気まぐれの産物といえよう
What joyous whims they are.
なんという
うれしい気まぐれだろう
She may look very young, but since she's lived a long life spanning over five centuries...
見た目は幼女のようだけれど
５世紀以上という
長い人生を生きている彼女は
Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 9
案外というか
Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 9
...the girl is perhaps surprisingly adept at being considerate in some ways.
Oshino Shinobu
Animation Number 9
割と
その辺の気遣いが
しっかりしているの
かもしれない
This is a tale from her past.
Animation Number 10
否 気遣いならぬ
あくまで気まぐれなのだろうが…
No, she's not being considerate, but acting on more of her whims.
Let's rewind her clock.
Animation Number 11
This time, we'll talk about how such whims of hers worked 400 years in the past.
Let's rewind her clock.
Animation Number 11
そんな彼女の気まぐれが
Let's rewind her clock.
Animation Number 11
400年前 どんなふうに
働いたかという話を
今回はしよう
Of course there is more to the story,
Animation Number 12
What kind of events she faced within this country 400 years ago.
400年前 彼女がこの国で
どういう目に遭ったのか
That past is linked to the present.
Animation Number 13
And what she's done.
そして 何をしたのか
As for the reason why,
Animation Number 14
It's a story of that sort.
As for the reason why,
Animation Number 14
そういう話だ
As for the reason why,
Animation Number 14
As usual
I helped others and they helped me in return,
Animation Number 14
Doing something despite being unable to do anything.
Well, I had someone read that part.
Animation Number 14
（阿良々木）
僕… 阿良々木 暦(こよみ)も
I
Animation Number 14
As for me, Araragi Koyomi...
I
Animation Number 14
...I'll tell the tale while reminiscing about her.
あいつのことを
思いながら話そう
I want you to think about it.
Animation Number 14
Let us begin
Shinobu Time         Part One
Font used in the video: HGP Mincho B
Animation Number 15
21st of August
Recap up to previous episode.
（阿良々木）
前回までのあらすじ
I, Araragi Koyomi, along with my vampiric partner, Oshino Shinobu...
僕 阿良々木 暦は
パートナーの吸血鬼…
...experienced a very common type of time travel together.
忍野 忍と共に
ありふれたタイムスリップを経験し
Partner
There, we failed to change history, and we dejectedly returned to the present time.
そして 歴史を変えることに失敗し
すごすごと
現代に帰ってきたのでした
終わり
The end.
Animation Number 21
The End
Mitsui Logistics
Personally, there was an emotional reason behind that time travel as well.
一応 あのタイムスリップには
我ながら感動的な理由があって
It was to prevent the loss of Hachikuji Mayoi...
それは
八九寺真宵(はちくじ まよい)が僅か10歳にして
その幼い命を
交通事故で亡くしてしまうのを
...who lost her life in a traffic accident at the young age of ten.
未然に防ごうとしての行為だった
In the end, when I asked her directly upon our dejected return after the battle was lost...
まあ 結局 すごすご
敗残して帰ってきてから
彼女に直接
聞いてみれば…
To defend my honor
Animation Number 26
(This is petty)
I wish to make this easy to follow
Animation Number 26
I didn't want to be revived or anything.
（八九寺）
別に私は
生き返りたくなんかないですよ
You did something completely useless, Self-Satisfied Araragi-san.
ムダなことしましたね
独り善がりな阿良々木さん
キャハ！
...was what she told me.
（阿良々木）
と言われてしまったのだが…
And so, now I was strolling back home together with Hachikuji Mayoi.
そんなわけで 僕は今
八九寺真宵と一緒に
テクテクと帰宅途中だった
After failing to change history by time traveling,
タイムスリップで
歴史を変えることに失敗し
I had returned to the present, only to find the start-of-term ceremony was already underway.
現代に帰ってきたときには
既に始業式は始まっちゃっていて
Senjougahara and
Animation Number 33
Hanekawa
might kill me twice over otherwise
Animation Number 33
And I still had to return Hachikuji's backpack to her.
僕は八九寺に
リュックサックを返して
やらなければならなかったのだ
Sensorily it was quite a while ago
Animation Number 34
On the timeline, it's just yesterday. August 20th.
時間軸的には
つい昨日 ８月20日
Ghost girl Hachikuji came over to my room and had forgotten her backpack there.
幽霊少女 八九寺が
僕の部屋に遊びに来て
そして
リュックサックを忘れていったのだ
While I was getting worked up about changing history...
僕が過去を変えようと
躍起になっていたとき
...Hachikuji had been wandering all over town in an attempt to retrieve her backpack from my house.
八九寺は 僕の家から
リュックサックを取り戻そうと
町じゅうを
ウロウロしていたのだった
But Hachikuji...
（阿良々木）
しかし 八九寺 やっぱ あれだな
You know, without a backpack, something about your character...
リュックサックがないと
お前って どこか…
...feels very faint.
（阿良々木）キャラが薄くなるよな
Light Green Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It's true that without my backpack, I look more like a slug than a snail.
確かにリュックサックがないと
私は蝸牛(かたつむり)ではなく
ナメクジっぽくなりますが
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Lives above ground
Part of various species
having spiral shells
Also called dendenmushi and maimai
Animation Number 44
Snail
Come to think of it, I heard that slugs and snails are the same thing.
そういえば 蝸牛とナメクジって
まあ 同じもんっちゃ
同じもんらしいんだよな
Something about a slug is a snail that's regressed from having a shell...
蝸牛から殻が退化したのが
ナメクジだとか
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
Though both are terrestrial mollusks,
unlike snails, slugs are often
considered stereotypically disgusting
Animation Number 44
Slug
A pitiless being
Animation Number 46
It feels weird that a shellfish would lose its shell by regression, yet have something left.
貝類から貝が退化して
残るものがあるというのも
不思議な感覚ですがね
If it were a human, wouldn't it be something like "I lost all my bones, but I'm still alive and well!"?
人間でいえば
骨がなくなったけど
まだ生きてるよ 元気だよ〜
Something like that
Animation Number 50
みたいなものなんでしょうか？
Yeah.
Animation Number 51
Oh well
If you think of a shell as an exoskeleton, then yeah.
（阿良々木）
貝を外骨格と見なせば
そうなんだろうけれど
But in terms of what it does, isn't it more like skin?
しかし 役割的には
どちらかといえば
皮膚じゃないのか？
I don't know. The impression of a hermit crab is pretty strong...
なんていうか ヤドカリの
イメージが強くありますから
...so it feels like you can take shells off of snails.
蝸牛の殻って取れそうなんですよね
Of course, if you actually did, they'd die.
実際に取ったら死んじゃいますけど
Apparently, some important stuff is in those shells.
結構 大事な中身が
詰まっているそうですから
Just like your backpack?
お前のリュックサックと同じか？
Shell
Animation Number 56
No, nothing inside my backpack is that important.
Shell
Animation Number 56
（八九寺）
いえ 私のリュックサックに
そこまで大事なものは
入ってませんけどね
It's just physiologically impossible to accept the current situation...
単に 自分の持ち物を
阿良々木さんに
預けているという現状が
...that my belongings are in your hands, Araragi-san.
生理的に嫌なだけであって
I'm not especially troubled without it.
別に なくても困りません
Hachikuji Mayoi will simply become Mayoi the Slug.
八九寺真宵が
ナメクジ真宵になるだけの話です
Then, come in for a bit, Hachikuji.
（阿良々木）
じゃあ 上がってけよ 八九寺
Huh?
Animation Number 63
は？　ご両親も妹さん
たちもいないであろう
Huh?
Animation Number 63
I have not lost my precautions as a girl...
...to the point that I'd enter your house when neither your parents nor sisters are present, Araragi-san.
阿良々木さんの家に
入るほど
私は女子として警戒心を
失ってはいないのですよ
Then, wait here for just a minute. I'll go grab your backpack immediately.
じゃあ ここで ちょっと待ってろ
お前のリュック
すぐに取ってくるから
10 seconds. Dash.
10秒　ダッシュ
Animation Number 67
Arrogant!
（阿良々木）横柄！
ハア ハア…
Hey, don't touch that, please! That's my stuff!
ちょっと 触んないでくださいよ
人の荷物に
Don't ask for the impossible...
（阿良々木）むちゃを言うなよ
Ah, now I have to get it cleaned.
（八九寺）
あ〜あ クリーニングに出さなきゃ
Hey, don't you think you've been disparaging me a little too much?
なあ… お前 さっきから
僕のこと嫌い過ぎてねえか？
I don't want that backpack anymore. Please dispose of it.
（八九寺）
もういりませんよ そんなリュック
捨てておいてください
No, if you don't have this, you're going to turn into Mayoi the Slug, right?
（阿良々木）
いや だから
これがなかったら お前
ナメクジ真宵になっちゃうだろ？
Why are you suspiciously trying to shove this back on me?
なんで そうやって
妙に押しつけようとするんですか
You must have wiretapped it or something.
さては盗聴器でも仕掛けましたね！
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Sheesh, you really are the worst, Araragi-san!
うっわ！　阿良々木さん 最低〜！
I'm being doubted too much here...
疑われ過ぎだろ 僕…
Yellow Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Hachikuji, do you have anything you want to eat?
八九寺
何か食べたいものとかあるか？
Yes, but as you can tell, I'm a ghost.
はあ… でも 私は
このとおり幽霊ですので
So if you were to spend lunchtime with me...
阿良々木さん もしも私と
ランチタイムということになれば
...people would look at you like those parents that order enough food for themselves and their late daughter.
阿良々木さんは
亡くなった娘さんの分まで
料理を注文する
ご両親みたいな目で
見られることになりますよ
Araragi
I don't care about that.
別にいいよ そんなの
Well, even though I said I'm treating, I'm a student facing entrance exams, so it'll be fast food.
まあ おごってやるっつっても
金のない受験生の話だから
ファーストフードだけどな
Fast Food
Are you unhappy?
Animation Number 98
There can be no unhappiness
in living off fast food, you know.
Animation Number 98
There can be no unhappiness
in living off fast food, you know.
Animation Number 98
There can be no unhappiness
in living off fast food, you know.
Animation Number 98
There can be no unhappiness
in living off fast food, you know.
Animation Number 98
Says you.
All right, hop on the bike. Let's ride double.
じゃあ 自転車に乗れよ
２人乗りだ
No, I don't want to be behind you, Araragi-san!
（八九寺）
嫌です！
阿良々木さんの後ろなんて
Dislike
Animation Number 101
Abhorrence
Shunning
Animation Number 101
And so, just now, I was expecting another one of these...
（阿良々木）
と… どうやら現在
I've only entered Araragi-san's home at night to watch over him?
Animation number 101
八九寺の中で
流行(はや)っているらしい
I've only entered Araragi-san's home at night to watch over him?
Animation number 101
To begin with, what you did yesterday was practically kidnapping you know?
By the time the series' ended there will be more novels, like so many zombies endlessly being brought back to life.
Animation number 101
..."I hate Araragi-san" responses that Mayoi seems to be infatuated with.
〝阿良々木さん
嫌いプレイ〞の返答が
By the time the series' ended there will be more novels, like so many zombies endlessly being brought back to life.
Animation number 101
There are a lot of things I'd like to eat, but none that I'd like to eat with Araragi-san.
またも返ってこようという
そのときだった
It had already become addicting to me, and I was waiting for the exact moment it would come.
早くも 僕的には癖になり
今か今かと待ち構えていた
その返答を
No, that was on purpose.
Animation Number 105
I st-stuttered.
It wasn't on purpose!?
Animation Number 105
But I couldn't hear it out to the end...
僕は最後まで聞くことは
できなかった
Araragi
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
（阿良々木）
なぜなら
Because we...
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
僕たちは
目撃してしまったからだ
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Araragi
...witnessed "it."
それを…
Animation Number 115
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
"It"
Animation Number 118
was a mystery.
Mystery.
Animation Number 118
This was my only answer.
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
Even the question of whether or not
it was an aberration was not one that we—or,
well, I—could answer.
Animation Number 118
I couldn't pinpoint what "it" was.
（阿良々木）
それが何なのか同定できなかった
Because I couldn't see "it" at all.
だって 僕には
それが見えなかったのだから
The fact that I couldn't see "it" doesn't mean that "it" was transparent.
見えないというのは
決して
透明であるという意味ではない
However, if you can't visually recognize something,
だって 視認できないということは
it means you can't "admit" the "perception" that "you can't see."
見えないという認識を
認められないということなのだから
I was witness to something I could not see.
Animation Number 124
I feel this is contradictory,
but that expression is
Animation Number 124
the most precise.
You can't realize that you can't see. In other words, it doesn't exist.
Animation Number 124
the most precise.
見えないことに気付かない
それは 換言すれば
いないということだ
Something you can't perceive cannot exist.
認識できないものは存在しない
At least within the human brain, such logic stands.
少なくとも 人間の脳の中では
そんな理論が成立する
Broad Daylight ——
Animation Number 127
The broad daylight of summer
Perfect visibility
Animation Number 127
And, in this case, I was able to perceive this invisible "thing."
Perfect visibility
Animation Number 127
で この場合 見えないそれを
僕は認識することができたのだ
The fact that I could perceive what I couldn't see...
見えないことを認識できた
Darkness—
Animation Number 130
Blackness, if you will.
...was because the "darkness" was right there.
だって そこには
“くらやみ”があったのだから
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
It was intuition.
Animation Number 135
It was instinct.
It was a terrible premonition.
Animation Number 135
Araragi
Please take us out of here!
（八九寺）出してください！
（阿良々木）分かってるよ！
I know!
Hachikuji!
（阿良々木）八九寺！
（八九寺）はい！
Yes!
Check behind us! Is that thing following us?
後方確認！
ついてきてるか？　さっきのやつ
Name
Hachikuji Mayoi
Let's see...
Name
Hachikuji Mayoi
ええっと…
Name
Hachikuji Mayoi
Something is chasing us!
なんか来てます！
Name
Hachikuji Mayoi
Something? What's it like?
なんか来てるって…
どんな感じに？
Well, it's like it's there before you know it.
えっと…
いえ 気が付いたら
そこにいる感じなんです
近くには いないんですけど
遠くもない感じで…
It's like it's not close to us, but it's also not that far away.
For someone like Hachikuji, that's a very vague way to express it.
（阿良々木）
八九寺にして
随分とあやふやな表現だ
But that is totally understandable. Because that "darkness" is invisible.
しかし それも無理からぬ
だって あの“くらやみ”は
見えないのだ
The fact that it's invisible means that you can't accurately gauge its distance.
見えないということは
距離感が正確には測れない
ということでもある
All right, got it! You don't have to look anymore!
（阿良々木）
よし 分かった！
もう確認しなくていい
Hachikuji! Cling onto my back!
八九寺 僕の背中にしがみつけ
Name
Hachikuji Mayoi
I refuse!
（八九寺）嫌です！
（阿良々木）断るな バカ
Don't refuse, idiot! The balance is off like this!
バランスが悪いんだよ！
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
With a smack of her lips not belike a little girl,
Hachikuji Mayoi reluctantly, I presume, clung to my back.
Animation Number 178
Should I throw off my backpack as well?
リュックサックも
捨てたほうがいいでしょうか？
No...
いや… 捨てなくていい
——
However
Animation Number 180
——
However
Animation Number 180
——
However
Animation Number 180
——
However
Animation Number 180
That aside.
...you don't have to!
But I can get it later!
でも あとで拾いに来れば…
It's all right!
いいんだって！
More importantly, Hachikuji, hold on tighter to me! As if you were going to fuse into me!
それより 八九寺
もっとギュッと抱きついてろ
僕と
一体化するくらいの気持ちで
（八九寺）はい！
Okay!
Push those breasts into me more!
もっと胸を押しつけるように！
Like this?
こうですか？
Hachikuji! With more rotation!
（阿良々木）
八九寺！
もっと回転させるようにだ
S-Sure!
（八九寺）は… はい！
Araragi-san!
阿良々木さん
What's wrong, twin boobs?
（阿良々木）
どうした？　ツインおっぱい
It's following us!
追ってきてます！
And it looks like it's getting closer...
なんか 近づいてきてるような…
I thought you couldn't tell?
距離感は つかめないはずじゃあ？
W-Well, I can't. I don't have a sense of distance.
いえ… そうなんですけど
距離感はありませんけど
圧迫感があるといいますか…
But I guess I'm feeling oppressed...
Aberrations that curse people just by looking at them do exist.
（阿良々木）
目撃するだけで
呪われてしまうような怪異(かいい)は
実在する
An aberration that's created on sight.
見られることで生じる怪異
Recognized
Animation Number 200
In other words, there's a chance that the "darkness" is an aberration that needs to be witnessed to take effect.
つまり
あの〝くらやみ〞が
目撃することが
It was an aberration.
Animation Number 200
発動条件の怪異だという
可能性はあるのだ
Stop
Animation Number 201
Pretending to dispel it like a Mikoshi-Nyuudou by looking
might not work.
Animation Number 201
Hachikuji, that's enough! Don't look!
八九寺！　いいから もう見るな
But! But, but...
でも… でもでも
Just stay quiet and kiss my back!
（阿良々木）
おとなしく僕の背中にキスしとけ！
O-Okay!
は… はい！
ムグ〜
（阿良々木）いっ…
Feelings
I glanced at
Animation Number 219
the darkness.
Hachikuji! Are you all right?
八九寺！　無事か？
I broke an antenna!
触角が１本 折れました
Isn't that a big deal?
大変なことじゃないのか？　それ
Or rather, do humans have organs that are antennae?
ていうか 人間に
触角なんて器官があったっけ？
My mistake! One of my two ponytails came loose!
間違いました
ツインテールが１本 ほどけました
I see...
そうか
Don't surprise me.
（阿良々木）
脅かすなあ…
And my blouse ripped a tiny bit around my shoulder.
あと ブラウスの肩の所が
ちょっとだけ破れました
Are you all right?
大丈夫なのか？
Yes, it was just my clothes...
はい 服だけです
But since my hair is half down and my clothes are torn...
ただ 髪が片方ほどけて
服が破れたので
Look
Left
and
Right
...I look like I was assaulted and about to be kidnapped by you, Araragi-san!
なんだかビジュアル的には 私
阿良々木さんに乱暴されて
誘拐されてる最中みたいな
絵面(えづら)になってます
That's not all right!
それは大丈夫じゃないな！
Koyomi     Monologue / Thoughts
Animation Number 240
My life from here on is in trouble.
Koyomi     Monologue / Thoughts
Animation Number 240
（阿良々木）
今後の僕の人生が大変だ
Koyomi     Monologue / Thoughts
Animation Number 240
（阿良々木）ぐっ…
Run the red light?
Animation Number 243
Don't run the red light?
Feeling Hachikuji on my back,
Animation Number 244
I couldn't ignore it.
I couldn't have her too.
Animation Number 244
However
Animation Number 246
Here, I failed.
Name
Hachikuji Mayoi
Yes
Animation Number 248
I foundered.
I strayed onto the car lane——
Animation Number 248
For Pedestrians
And Bicycles Only
More      Seconds
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Red Light
Animation Number 250
Red means stop.
Animation Number 251
Stop
Turn Right
Self-Destruction
Animation Number 254
Suicide Bombing
Completely useless escape attempts.
Animation Number 254
Wherever I tried to turn,
there it was
That darkness.
Animation Number 255
Central Road
Width Reduction
Reduced Capacity
But
Animation Number 258
I really want to get Hachikuji out of this.
I have to let her escape.
Animation Number 259
I have to let her escape!
I have to rescue this girl—
Animation Number 259
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Unlimited Rulebook.
（斧乃木(おののき)）
アンリミテッド･ルールブック
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 261
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 261
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 261
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 261
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 261
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 261
（阿良々木）うっ…
（八九寺）きゃっ！
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Devil boy...
（斧乃木）鬼のおにいちゃん
（阿良々木）あっ…
Over here.
Safety First
（斧乃木）こっちだよ
Huh? Oh, it's you, Ononoki-chan. Why are you here?
（阿良々木）え？
あれ 斧乃木ちゃん…
どうして 君が ここに？
What are you talking about? We just met yesterday.
Safety First
何 言ってんの？
昨日 会ったところじゃない
Did we really?
Animation Number 280
Walk Slowly on Construction Site
T-Thank...
ああ ありが…
Safety First
It's a bit early to say your thanks...
礼を言うのは ちょっと早い… かな
Safety First
Devil boy, what is that?
鬼のおにいちゃん 何？　あれ
（阿良々木）
え？　なんだ 斧乃木ちゃん
What, Ononoki-chan? Wasn't your role to suddenly appear, save me...
君は いきなり現れて
僕を助けてくれ
...and then explain everything to me?
そして 全てを説明してくれる
役割の子ではないのか？
That's troubling if you expect all that convenience from me...
Safety First
そんな都合のいいことを
一身に求められても困る… かも
You don't seem too sure.
Animation Number 286
Walk Slowly on Construction Site
Where's Hachikuji?
八九寺は！
You're too weak mentally.
Animation Number 293
I'm disappointed.
My, my. I helped you on a whim here...
（斧乃木）
やれやれ
うっかり助けてしまったけれど
こんなことなら
放っておけばよかった… かな
...but if I'd known it'd be like this, I would've left you alone.
It looks like I got myself involved in something I don't exactly comprehend.
どうやら僕は
よく分からないことに
巻き込まれてしまったらしい
Talk about hard luck.
とんだハードラックだよ
Don't tell me you should've left us alone. Life is a very precious thing.
Walk Slowly on Construction Site
“こんなことなら放っておけば
よかった”とか言うなよ
命は貴重だぜ
Funny how an undead vampire says that.
不死身の吸血鬼が言うよね
Is that girl the ghost you were talking about yesterday?
その女の子が
昨日言ってた幽霊かい？
She's got a backpack on her back. So you were able to safely return it to her. I'm glad.
リュックサック背負ってるし
無事に返せたんだね
よかった
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 299
Yesterday?
（阿良々木）昨日…
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 299
Was that yesterday? It's seems so long ago that I don't remember.
（阿良々木）
言ったのかな？
前のことすぎて覚えてない
Devil boy.
（斧乃木）鬼のおにいちゃん
（阿良々木）ん？
How do we go about this?
どうしたい？
（阿良々木）どうしたいって？
Safety First
Against that.
（斧乃木）あれと…
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 306
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 306
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 306
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 306
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 306
Unlimited Rulebook
Rules with many exceptions
Animation Number 306
Pointing at things fulfills its requirements.
I have first-hand experience of its power.
Animation Number 306
Fight it? Or run from it?
戦う？　それとも逃げる？
Run from it.
逃げる
Fight it? That thing implies nothing of the sort.
戦うとか
そういうもんじゃねえだろ あれは
Right. I think so too.
（斧乃木）だよね　僕も そう思う
Then, we're escaping. Devil boy, hold on to that girl.
じゃあ 逃げるよ
鬼のおにいちゃん その子を抱えて
Got it.
分かった
Quietly. Make as little noise as possible.
なるべく静かに
音を立てずに ゆっくりとね
And slowly. If you move too abruptly, that thing might react to your movement and attack us.
急に動いたら
あいつ それに反応して
襲いかかってくる
かもしれないし
Fitting animal
Animation Number 313
Safety First
I think you had some extraneous movement there.
余計な動作が
含まれていた気がしたけど
What are you talking about? What if there's an aberration hiding up her skirt?
何を言う
スカートの中に怪異がいたら
どうするんだ
Like I know, idiot.
知らねえよ バカ
She was rude and upset.
Animation Number 328
Then...
Unlimited Rulebook, secession version.
アンリミテッド･ルールブック
離脱版
Animation Number 336
Radius
Forbidden
Entry Prohibited
Entry
For
We
apologize
for any
inconvenience
and ask
for your
cooperation.
We
apologize
for any
inconvenience
and ask
for your
cooperation.
Danger Zone Ahead
Entry
Prohibited
Danger from Above
Danger
Danger Zone Ahead
Please don't
obstruct
construction
Please don't
obstruct
construction
We're sorry
for any
inconvenience
We're sorry
for any
inconvenience
Please don't
obstruct
construction
Please don't
obstruct
construction
Danger
Entry
Prohibited
I couldn't escape from the "darkness" no matter how hard I pedaled.
（阿良々木）
僕が あれだけ頑張って
自転車をこいでも
逃げられなかった“くらやみ”から
Ononoki-chan, while literally holding on to two good-for-nothings, managed an admirable escape.
斧乃木ちゃんは
文字どおりの足手まといを
２人 抱えたままで
見事 逃げきってみせた
What you actually did looked like...
（阿良々木）
実際に やったことといえば
ただ両足で
...nothing more than just jumping with all your strength from both feet.
思いっ切りジャンプしただけに
見えたんだけどな
No, you got it right, devil boy.
（斧乃木）
いや それで合ってるよ
鬼のおにいちゃん
I made it sound fancy by saying secession version, but I just simply escaped.
離脱版なんて
格好つけた言い方をしたけれど
単純に逃げただけだ
Simply?
単純にって…
But in a three-dimensional way.
ただし 立体的にね
You had proven to me that it's meaningless to try to escape two-dimensionally.
平面的に逃げても意味がないのは
鬼のおにいちゃんが
証明してくれてたから
So I thought maybe it wouldn't have countermeasures for vertical movement.
案外 上下の動きには
対応できないんじゃないかと思って
That was the bullseye.
ドンピシャだったね
Devil boy, you have quite a bit of muscle.
鬼のおにいちゃん
結構 筋肉質だね
（阿良々木）あ？
Good muscles. Yup.
いい筋肉だ　うん
（阿良々木）あ…
Good muscles. You must work out. Good muscles.
いい筋肉だね
鍛えてるんだね
I didn't notice while they were covered by clothes, but they are good muscles indeed.
服の上からだと
分かりにくかったけど
実に いい筋肉だ
I think you should stay like that forever.
ずっと その格好でいたら
いいんじゃないかな
鬼のおにいちゃんは
もっと筋肉をアピールするべきだよ
You should appeal your muscles more to the world.
You have an amazing thin-yet-macho body.
すばらしい細マッチョだと思う
Can we talk about something else now...
Animation Number 362
But for now, what I want to know about is that "darkness."
しかし さしあたって
今 知りたいのは
あの“くらやみ”についてだぜ
Ononoki-chan, you really have no clue?
斧乃木ちゃん
本当に何か心当たりはないのか？
I told you, I don't know!
だから 知らないって
Alternatively, don't you have any idea yourself, devil boy?
大体
鬼のおにいちゃんのほうにこそ
心当たりは ないのかい？
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 369
A clue, huh...
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 369
（阿良々木）
心当たりねえ…
Koyomi   Voice / Speech
Animation Number 369
I suppose so.
Animation Number 370
I have too many.
You could say my entire life consists of clues.
Animation Number 370
No idea.
分かんねえ
It's not like I'm a specialist in aberrations either.
僕は怪異の専門家ってわけじゃ
ないんだしな
I'm nothing more than a commonplace quasi-vampire that goes to high school.
僕は あくまで
どこにでもいる
吸血鬼もどきの高校生なんだから
I don't think that's commonplace...
どこにでもは いないと思うけど
Or rather, even thinking back on all the aberrations I've had to deal with...
つうか 今まで相手にしてきた
怪異を思い返してみても…
Oshino Shinobu
Vampire
Vampire, cat, crab, snail, monkey, snake, bee, bird...
吸血鬼 猫 蟹(かに) 蝸牛
Cat
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Crab
Senjougahara Hitagi
Snail
Hachikuji Mayoi
Monkey
Kanbaru Suruga
猿 蛇 蜂に 鳥
Monkey
Kanbaru Suruga
Snake
Sengoku Nadeko
Bee
Araragi Karen
Phoenix
Araragi Tsukihi
...and a corpse.
それに… 死体か
It feels different.
何か違うんだよな
あんな抽象的な
“くらやみ”そのものみたいな怪異
I've never seen an aberration so vague. Like it was "darkness" itself.
見たことねえ
What kind of an aberration-induced phenomenon is that?
どういう怪異現象なんだ？　あれ
White Scene
Animation Number 'none'
"Darkness," huh...
（斧乃木）“くらやみ”か
Well, that "thing" probably is the "darkness," but..
まあ 確かに あれは
“くらやみ”なんだろうけれど…
ん？　何だよ
What is it?
Well, how to put it...
いや なんというか
相手にしてるのが
It would be nice if what we're dealing with really is just the "darkness."
本当に〝くらやみ〞なら
いいんだけどね
What do you mean? No matter how you look at it, it was "darkness."
どういう意味だ？
どう見たって
あれは“くらやみ”じゃねえか
That's why we can't see it, right?
（斧乃木）
だから 見えないんだろう？
The possibility that the black blob was...
あの黒い塊は
ただの怪異に付随する現象という
可能性のほうが
...merely a phenomenon affixed to an ordinary aberration is a lot higher.
ずっと高いよ
Oh, that's what you mean...
ああ そういう意味…
Well, if we get into that, I'm not sure if we even "dealt with it" at all.
（斧乃木）
まっ それを言いだしたら
相手にしているのかどうかも
分かんないけどね
It's not necessarily the case that it showed up to go after you.
あれが鬼のおにいちゃんを狙って
現れたものだとは限らないわけで…
Just like how phenomenons such as storms and typhoons don't target a particular human.
台風とか嵐とかの気象現象が
人間を狙っているとは
限らないように
No, but that thing was clearly chasing after me and Hachikuji.
いや でも あれは明らかに
僕と八九寺を追ってきていたぜ
（斧乃木）そうなんだけどさ
I know, but...
Big Sister might know something about this...
おねえちゃんなら
何か知ってるかもしれないけれど
Kagenui Yotsugi
Animation Number 394
Violent Exorcist
...but I can't contact her right now.
今 僕は おねえちゃんとは
連絡が取れないからな
She's an old acquaintance of Oshino's
Animation Number 396
By the way, where and what is Kagenui-san doing right now?
ちなみに影縫(かげぬい)さんって
今 どこで何をしてるんだ？
She's probably at work, right?
多分 そっちも仕事なんだろ？
Work is work, yeah, but the details are of course a secret.
（斧乃木）
そりゃ 仕事は仕事だけど
細かいことは
秘密に決まってるじゃないか
Trying to probe stuff out of me? Such impudence.
何を探りを入れてるんだよ
ずうずうしい
I wasn't trying to be impudent by asking...
別に ずうずうしいつもりで
聞いたわけではないが…
I was trying to be polite
Animation Number 400
The duty of confidentiality of an Exorcist
was stronger than I anticipated.
Animation Number 400
Well, even if we can't contact Kagenui-san, there's no problem.
まあ 影縫さんに
連絡が取れなくても
別に問題はねえよ
I'll figure everything out come evening anyway.
どうせ 夜になったら
全て分かるわけだし
（斧乃木）ん？　どうして？
Why? Do you suddenly turn into a genius come evening, devil boy?
夜になったら
鬼のおにいちゃんは いきなり
頭脳明晰(めいせき)になるとでもいうの？
I don't have such a convenient function.
（阿良々木）
そんな便利な機能は僕にはない
Simply put, Shinobu will wake up.
単に 忍が起きるってだけだ
Shinobu is the lord of aberrations after all. I think she's familiar with all sorts of them.
忍は あれで怪異の王だからな
怪異については詳しいはずだし
On top of that, she got special lectures for several months...
しかも その上
影縫さんと同じく
専門家であるところの忍野メメから
...from Oshino Meme, a specialist just like Kagenui-san.
数か月間にわたる英才教育を
受けてるからな
I'm sure that she has some knowledge about that "darkness" too.
きっと
あの“くらやみ”についても
何らかの知識を
有しているはずなんだぜ
So if Shinobu wakes up, I'll know exactly what that "darkness" is.
だから 忍が起きたら
あの“くらやみ”の正体は
判明するはずなんだ
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Heh...
（斧乃木）
ケッ 信用ならないね
Red Scene
Animation Number 'none'
I don't trust the knowledge of such a senile geezer...
あんな後期高齢者の
知識なんて
Stop calling Shinobu a senile geezer.
忍のことを
後期高齢者と呼ぶのを やめろ
It's true Shinobu might not even know what that "darkness" really is...
確かに忍も
あの“くらやみ”が何なのかを
知っているとは限らない
But Ononoki-chan, that's fine in its own way.
でも 斧乃木ちゃん
それでも別に
いいっちゃいいんだよ
Why?
どうして？
（阿良々木）
忍は 怪異を食うからな
Shinobu eats aberrations.
Black Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Whatever that mysterious thing turns out to be, she'll swallow it whole.
あの正体不明の正体が
何であったところで
丸飲みにしてくれるさ
And I'll ask Hanekawa to explain the mystery of the "darkness" sometime later.
あの“くらやみ”の謎なんて
後日 羽川(はねかわ)にでも聞いて
教えてもらうさ
Hanekawa? Who's that?
はねかわ？　それは誰？
Someone who knows everything.
何でも知ってるヤツ
I think there's something wrong about being completely reliant on someone else like that.
（斧乃木）どうかと思うけどね
そんなふうに
誰かに頼りっきりになるのは
Though it's weird for me to say this now, because I just happened to rescue you, devil boy.
鬼のおにいちゃんを
ついつい助けてしまった僕が
言うのもなんだけどさ
Lilac Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Well, see you.
じゃ これで
See you? What, you're already going home?
（阿良々木）これでって…
なんだよ 帰っちゃうのか？
I'm not going home. I'm going back to work.
（斧乃木）
帰るというか 仕事に戻るんだよ
Weren't you going to be at my side forever and protect me from harm?
一生 僕に付き添って
僕の身を
守ってくれるんじゃないのか？
What kind of thought is that?
どんな発想だよ
A joke. You did a great job protecting me, even if it was once.
冗談だ
一度でも よく守ってくれたと思う
Come to think, I had forgotten to say my thanks. Thank you.
そういえば
お礼を言いそびれていたな
ありがとう
I'll repay you in some way.
この恩は何らかの形で返すよ
With muscles?
筋肉で？
No, with something other than muscles...
いや… 筋肉以外の何かで
But if you insist,
Animation Number 434
I could gouge out one of my abs
and present it to you...
Animation Number 434
For someone like me, who doesn't know when she'll be gone from this world,
（斧乃木）
いつ この世から
消えてしまうか分からない
僕のような立場の者からすれば
gratitude and favors are basically repaid at once.
恩やら貸しやらは
即返しが基本だよ
At once
Animation Number 436
Repaid at once...
At once
Animation Number 436
（阿良々木）即返し…
At once
Animation Number 436
Then is there something I can do right now?
じゃあ 何か
今すぐ僕にできることはないか？
Something you can do right now?
（斧乃木）
今すぐ鬼のおにいちゃんに
できることねえ…
Hmm, let's see.
う〜ん そうだな
Though what I can do is very limited, you can try asking for anything.
まあ 僕にできることなんて
限られているけど
何でも言ってみてくれよ
言うだけでも
Whatever it is, it doesn't hurt to ask.
Devil boy...
（斧乃木）鬼のおにいちゃん
（阿良々木）あ？
（斧乃木）こっち向いて
Look this way... smooch.
チュッ
They were locked.
Animation Number 448
Out of nowhere.
W-What the ellemenopee...
なっ なにぬねの…
Quearessteeu.
らりるれろ
（阿良々木）あああ…
Oh no, you cheated!
あ〜あ 浮気した
You're such a bad guy, devil boy.
ダメな男だな 鬼のおにいちゃんは
What is she even saying?!
Animation Number 455
With a completely straight face, too!
Well, I just wanted to teach you that trust and stuff like that all crumble away so easily.
まあ 信頼関係とかなんとか
そういうのって
こうもたやすく
壊れるものだってことを
教えてあげたかったのさ
I think that was me adding to the gratitude you need to reciprocate instead of you doing so now.
恩を返してもらったというよりは
更に恩を着せてやったという
感じかな
You have quite a bit now to repay, devil boy.
随分な厚着だね 鬼のおにいちゃん
But well, that was a bit of a relief.
でも まあ
ちょっとはスカッとしたか
Directed at Shinobu
Animation Number 459
A spiteful remark
Or is it...
Animation Number 459
See you.
じゃ…
まあ 頑張って生き残ってよね
Well, do your best and survive... In this game that you don't know the rules of...
ルールの分からない このゲームを
This isn't a game.
これはゲームなんかじゃねえよ
Then what is it?
じゃあ 何？
Animation Number 467
The condition that was born from Ononoki-chan leaving the premises...
（阿良々木）
斧乃木ちゃんが
この場を去ったことで生まれた
更なる状況というやつに 戦慄！
Shudders!
Since Hachikuji's asleep, I can do whatever I like to her right now...
（阿良々木）
八九寺が寝てるってことは
何をしても いいってことだよな
Yellow Scene
Animation Number 'none'
Vampire punch!
（忍）吸血鬼…
パ〜ンチ！
（阿良々木）ぐわっ！
Alarm
Press hard
Sigh, I guess that was a close call.
（忍）ハア…
危機一髪といった
ところのようじゃの
I guess I woke up with good timing.
いいタイミングで
目が覚めたようじゃ
The right time, eh?
Animation Number 496
Haven't you only gotten like two hours of actual sleep?
（阿良々木）
お前 実質２時間くらいしか
寝てないんじゃねえの？
My sleep was rather light. I couldn't get any decent rest in.
どうも眠りが浅い
全然 熟睡できんかった
I couldn't get rid of any fatigue at all.
まるっきり
疲れが取れんかったわい
What happened?
何があったのじゃ？
I messed up
Animation Number 498
（阿良々木）え？
（忍）言っておろう
I messed up
Animation Number 498
I told you already. We're paired up mentally now.
お前様とわしとは
精神的に
ペアリング
されておるのじゃから
If you're unsettled, that gets passed on to me.
お前様の動揺は
わしに伝達される
All I could think of is that something happened to you, and therefore my sleep became lighter.
お前様に何かあった
故に わしの眠りが
浅くなったとしか考えられんが
Oh, that's...
ああ それは…
That "darkness." It's because it chased me. No doubt about it.
（阿良々木）
あの“くらやみ”
あれに追われたせいだ
間違いない
By the way, you...
ところで お前様
Eh? What is it?
（阿良々木）え… 何かな？
Don't you have something you have to tell me?
わしに何か
言っておくことはないかの？
Let's beat around the bush
Animation Number 513
Hey Shinobu, you can change the length of your hair at will, right?
なあ 忍
お前の髪の長さって
そういえば
自由に調整できるんだよな
If you're talking about how you kissed that little shikigami girl, I totally saw it.
お前様と式神(しきがみ)童女との
キスシーンなら目撃したぞ
Too sharp
Um, Shinobu-san...
（阿良々木）あの 忍さん…
Oh, an apology? An apology?
（忍）おっ 謝罪か？　謝罪か？
I'm looking forward to this. How is this man going to apologize?
楽しみじゃのう
どんなふうに謝るんじゃろうな
About how he shoved me, his lifelong partner, aside...
この男は
生涯のパートナーである
このわしを差し置いて
...and performed acts with some outsider, a little shikigami girl.
あんなよそ者の式神童女と
行為に及んだことについて
Hey, Shinobu...
あの 忍…
（忍）フンッ
I'm sorry, but listen!
ごめん！　まあ 聞けよ
I want to know as soon as possible.
Animation Number 518
I want her to tell me.
"Darkness."
Animation Number 518
Hmph! I refuse, you fool.
フンッ お断りじゃ 愚か者
Keep out, oafs
Oaf
You chitchat with all sorts of girls on a regular basis.
普段(ふだん)から さんざんいろんな女子(おなご)と
雑談ばかりしておるくせに
Yet you always dispense with the small talk when you have something you want to talk about.
いざ自分が
話したいことがあるときだけ
ムダ話抜きで会話を進めようなどと
Not only is it symbolic,
Animation Number 523
but also downright heretical.
Such a convenience for you may be forgiven by the heavens, but not by me!
そんな調子のいいまねは
天が許しても わしが許さん！
W-What are you doing to me!
なっ… 何をするんじゃ！　お前様
Are you an Italian?
イ… イタリア男か！
Just listen to my story.
いいから聞け 僕の話を
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
The midsummer adventure was completely and utterly pointless. Why the hell did you waste one whole volume on that nonsense?
You must be stupid. Just die.
Oh wait, you're half-vampire so you can't really die.
What are we ever going to do with you? Geez.
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
Well, being detested to the bone by a young girl is a rare experience that might
actually be worth celebrating, so I'm not exactly against putting up with it. That said,
Animation Number 549
So we headed back together to my place so that I could return the backpack to her.
（阿良々木）
とりあえずは
そのリュックサックを
返してやるために
僕の家に ２人で一緒に帰ったんだ
In a friendly, friendly, very friendly manner.
仲良く 仲良く
とても仲良くな
Why are you stressing "friendly" so much?
お前様 なぜに そんなにも
“仲良く”を強調するのじゃ
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
Just so we're clear, I swear on every God's name that I haven't laid a finger
on Hachikuji's backpack since she forgot it at my place yesterday.
I might've been called a cruel man with a lolita complex, but my moral fiber
hasn't deteriorated to the extent that I put my hands on girls' private property.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
I'm a gentleman.
A caballero, I say.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
This is a good time. I'm a vampire, so I don't need to be all that regular with my food intake.
However, old habits die hard, and Hachikuji's with me right now, too.
It might not be a bad idea to have lunch with her.
Animation Number 549
...and that's how the story goes. How about it?
て… 話なんだけど どうかな？
It's fine if you have no clue.
まあ 心当たりがないなら
心当たりがないで
全然いいんだけれど
You told me such a stupid story, you brat.
（忍）
つまらん話を聞かせおって
このガキが
Her nuance
Animation Number 551
was a bit different.
Quite different.
Animation Number 551
Thanks to that, I'm reminded of something unpleasant.
おかげで嫌なことを思い出したわい
（阿良々木）え？
（忍）いや…
No...
You know what kind of aberration that is, don't you—
Animation Number 553
As you are already half-aware...
（忍）
お前様も既に半分
気付いておるように
...that "darkness" is not an aberration.
その“くらやみ”は
怪異ではない
（阿良々木）あ…
That phenomenon has no name.
その現象には名前がない
Bluntly.
Animation Number 555
She declared.
That thing you call the "darkness" is something I have seen in the past.
お前様が“くらやみ”と呼ぶ
それを
わしは その昔
見たことがあるんじゃよ
What? How long ago are you talking about?
（阿良々木）
なんだよ その昔って
どれくらい昔のことだ？
About 400 years ago.
（忍）400年くらい前かの
400 years? If I recall, that was...
（阿良々木）
400年？　それって 確か…
Right.
そう… 前に わしが
この国を訪れたときじゃ
It was the previous time that I visited this country.
In other words, back when I made my first minion.
つまり １人目の眷属(けんぞく)を作った
そのときじゃ
Back then, I was entangled in that "darkness."
わしは そのとき
あの“くらやみ”に
巻き込まれたのじゃ
No, I guess I should say that I was swallowed up by it.
否 のみ込まれたと言うべきか
Swallowed up...
（阿良々木）のみ… 込まれ…
I'd rather not speak of it, but in this situation, I can't really keep it that way.
（忍）
できれば話したくもないんじゃが
こうなってしまえば
そういうわけにも
いかんのじゃろうな
Now that "it" has surfaced, the worst case scenario is if I leave it be,
あれが出現してしまった以上
放っておけば 最悪…
this entire town will fall to ruin.
この町の全てが滅びる
Thus it begins.
Animation Number 564
Late as it may be.
Preview
Dialogue Script - Nisio Isin
4-Koma Illustrations - Haritama Hiroki
Preview
Karen here!
（火憐）火憐(かれん)だぜ！
（月火）月火(つきひ)だよ！
And Tsukihi!
I'm Tsukihi!
Together, we're the Fire Sisters!
We're the Fire Sisters!!
Devil!
（火憐･月火）
２人合わせて
ファイヤーシスターズ
Our previews have come a long way, haven't they?
What? You want to
hear about my past?
（火憐）
私たちの予告も
すっかり
板についてきたぜ
The fact they became a full-fledged program does not come as a surprise.
（月火）
もはや 他番組から
予告のオファーが来ても
不思議じゃない
It's no wonder they came this far indeed.
（火憐）
クイズ番組から
オファーが来ても
不思議じゃねえ！
Preview Quiz!
（月火）予告編クイズ！
（火憐）クイズ！
Quiz!
As you wish, I'll kill some time talking about it.
Sounds interesting!
Yay!
There are 53 cards in a card game, however...
（月火）
トランプといえば
53枚ですが
（火憐）
ですが？
However?
What sort of a number is that? To begin with, having 13 ranks for each suit is silly; it just feels so incomplete!
（月火）
なんで こんな
中途半端な数なの？
そもそも
それぞれのマークごとに
13枚っていうとこから
もう中途半端は
始まってるじゃない
Excited
Let's put our
heart into it.
Truth is I'm happy to do it.
Incomplete indeed!
（火憐）
中途半端が始まってる！
So let's go with 10 ranks for each suit, and we don't need the joker: 40 cards total.
（月火）
マーク１つにつき10枚
合計40枚
ジョーカーとかは
いらない
これでトランプは
分かりやすくなると思う
I believe it will make card games simpler.
Simpler, but so much blander.
（火憐）
分かりやすいけど
味がなくなったぞ
Talking
Let's begin then!
Eh?!
How long will it take?
Maybe 50 cards would be even better? Then it can't be helped; let's add a "Moon" suit to the set.
（月火）
50枚のほうが
もっと分かりやすいかな
じゃあ やむをえない
月のマークのカードを
10枚 追加してもいいよ
Please, at least make it a "Fire" suit!
（火憐）
そこは
せめて炎のマークにしろ
Next Time
Shinobu Time Part 2
（火憐･月火）
次回「鬼物語 第２話
しのぶタイム 其ノ貳(そのに)」
Next time! Onimonogatari Episode 2!
Shinobu Time, Part 2.
Talking
400 years make
for a long story...
Speaking of cards, I still don't see why the "One" card is called "Ace"...
（月火）
大体
１をエースっていうのに
まだ私は納得していない
You sound just like the Queen of Hearts.
（火憐）
振る舞いが赤の女王だぜ